(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-26T08:45:09.578853",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
モンスター モンスター
Monster! Monster!
モンモンモンモン モンスター
Mon-mon-mon-mon Monster!
モンスター モンスター モンスターズライフ
Monster! Monster! Monster's life!
モンスター モンスター
Monster! Monster!
モンモンモンモン モンスター
Mon-mon-mon-mon Monster!
モンスター モンスター モンスターズライフ
Monster! Monster! Monster's life!
ひとつ！
Firstly!
人目ばっかり気にしないで
Don't worry about what others think,
大胆に、かつ慎重に ターゲットを決める
Be bold yet careful and pick your target!
ふたつ！
Secondly!
挨拶はほどほどに ココロの準備が済んだら
Keep greetings brief, once your heart is ready,
いざ、陣中に！
Now to the front lines!
みっつ！
Thirdly!
見つけたスキは即座に狙い定め
Spot an opening, take aim instantly,
撃つべし撃つべし撃つべし撃つべしっ！
Shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot!
よっつ！
Fourthly!
遠慮は必要ないさ あとは確実に
No need to hold back, just surely
ハートを仕留めるだけで
Pierce their heart!
愛だったら、ほんのちょっとでいい
If it's love, just a little bit is fine,
それより、何より、欲望のおもむくままさ
More than anything, follow your desires!
さあ、ねぇダーリン！
Now, hey darling!
キミがいるから最強じゃない？
Aren't I the strongest with you here?
ずっと一緒なら最高じゃない？
Isn't it the best if we're always together?
この先何があったって
No matter what happens from here on,
キミとなら ALL OK！
With you, it's all OK!
もはやこれは紛れもない
This is already without a doubt
宇宙で一番の LOVE なんじゃない？
The greatest love in the universe, right?
答え待ちきれないんだよ、もう
I can't wait for your answer anymore!
最高速 Fall in Love！
Full-speed Fall in Love!
いっつ！
Fifthly!
攻撃は最大の防御
Offense is the best defense,
休むヒマもなく即
With no time to rest, instantly
撃つべし撃つべし撃つべし撃つべしっ！
Shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot!
むっつ！
Sixthly!
瞬間で伝えていくんだ大事なのは目と目を合わせること
Convey it in an instant, what matters is meeting eyes!
愛しても、愛し合っても
Even if you love, even if you love each other,
足らない、もっと
It's not enough, even more!
本能さらけ出していこうねぇダーリン！
Let's bare our instincts, hey darling!
キミがいるから最強じゃない？
Aren't I the strongest with you here?
感じ合えるなら最高じゃない？
Isn't it the best if we can feel each other?
ほかに何も無くたって
Even if there's nothing else,
大丈夫です ALL OK！
It's alright, all OK!
生まれた場所は問題じゃない
Where you were born doesn't matter,
この一瞬こそが LOVE なんじゃない？
Isn't this very moment LOVE?
ハートまだとめないでよ、そう
Don't stop your heart yet, yes—
ハート まだ 止めないでよ
Heart, don't stop yet,
そう 最高速
Yes, maximum speed!
Ah たとえば世界が止まっても
Ah, even if the world were to stop,
胸の高鳴りは止まらない
the throbbing in my chest won't stop,
全開でいこう！
Let's go full throttle!
ねぇ だいりーん キミがいるから最強じゃない？
Hey darling! Aren't you the strongest because you're here?
ずっと一緒なら最高じゃない？
Isn't it wonderful if we're always together?
この先何があったって
No matter what happens from now on,
キミとなら all ok!
with you, it's all OK!
もはやこれは紛れもない 宇宙で一番の love なんじゃない？
This is unquestionably, without a doubt, the greatest love in the entire universe, isn't it?
答え待ちきれないんだよもう 最高速
I can't wait for the answer anymore—maximum speed,
Fall in love!
モンスター モンスター…
Monster, monster...
生まれた場所は問題じゃない
Where we were born doesn't matter at all,
この一瞬こそが love なんじゃない？
isn't this exact moment what love is all about?
ハート まだ 止めないでよ
Don't stop your heart yet,
そう 最高速
Yes, at maximum speed,
Fall in love!
ありがとー！ というわけでみなさん、いかがでしたでしょうか？
Thank you so much! So everyone, how was that?
アイドルソロで踊るというのは、かっこいいかったですか？
Dancing solo as an idol—was it cool?
ええー！ と言うわけでここからはですね、
Yay! So from here on,
なんとねねが日頃ね、配信でもやっている、え、サイイン会をですね、行ってみたいと思いますー！
We're going to hold a sign-signing session that Nene usually does on her streams!
どうやって今日もやるかっていうとみんな、みんなにビックリしたかもしれない、今日はね、この画面に、なんとねねサインしていきたいと思いますー！
How are we doing it today? You might be surprised, but today Nene is going to sign right on this screen!
どれどれ？ かっこよかった？
Let's see. Was it cool?
わー、ダンスすごかった？ わー、うれしー、ありがとう！
Wow, the dance was amazing? Yay! I'm so happy, thank you!
じゃサインしていこうな！ １発目の金スキー、１発目、よいしょあ、ちょ、ちょっと待ってよ！
Now let's do the signing! First gold... wait, wait a second!
あー、ありがと、そう、ねね、ちょっと、手つき分かんなくなっちゃう、難しい！
Ah, thank you. Yeah, Nene is getting a bit clumsy with her hand movements, it's hard!
どうどう？ すごくない？ すごくない？ あの、あれにそっくり、プロ、プロ声優にたいせーなんさ。
How is it? Isn't it amazing? It looks just like that, like professional voice actors.
めっちゃぽいじゃん、なんか。あれ、ハリウッドっぽいじゃん？
It looks so like it. Kind of like, Hollywood-esque?
わ、すごいすごいこれ。どんどんやっていきたいと思いますし、もうだめだ、自分の文字もう出ない、全部しなきゃいけないからね。
Wow, this is amazing. We'll keep going, but no, I can't even read my own writing anymore because I have to do it all.
見てこれ、できてるんだよ、マジで！
Look at this, it's actually working!
すごすぎーる！ 息が、息が続かない！
This is too amazing! I'm running out of breath!
ちょっと最後もかいちゃく、な、次なんて書いてほしい？ え？
Let's write the last one too. What do you want me to write next? Eh?
そ、最後もしようかな？ よ、もういっずね！
Shall I do the last one too? Yo, one more!
あ、いいぞ、いいぞ！ はい、じゃあみんないっぱい、えっと、すすして！
Ah, nice, nice! Yes, everyone, lots of... uh, proceed!
わ、すごいすごい。あ、そうだ、ねっこう、ねっこうわないと！ 一緒にね、ねっこのみんなと一緒のステージでね、盛り上がりしたからちょっとねこ、ねこおいで！ ねこくちおいで！
Wow, that's amazing. Oh right, Neko, we gotta do Neko! Since we're hyping it up together on stage with all the Nekos, come here Neko!
あ、入ってきたね、今！ あ、来た来た来た来た、あ！ ちょっとちょっとここ、ここに、ここにいて、ここに！
Ah, they came in now! Ah, they're here, here! Wait, wait, here, stay right here!
どうしよう、えーっと、えー、今日は2022、3月14？ 今日ホワイトデーよ！
What should I do? Um, today is 2022, March 14? Today is White Day!
あじゅ！ まちがえちゃった！ 一緒にまちがえちゃった！ 10、あ、ちょっと待ってよ！ ちょっとちがくなって、えーっと、13！
Aju! I messed up! We messed up together! 10, ah, wait a minute! It got a bit different, um, 13!
え、3.13？ 2022.3.13？ ねぇみんな、あ、なれている？ ちゃんと？ あ、なれてるの？ 本当？
Eh, 3.13? 2022.3.13? Hey everyone, ah, are you used to it? Really? Ah, you're used to it? Really?
ねこ、ねこのみんなど？ ね、あいずの慣れている？ ちゃんと？ あ、なれてるね、本当？ はい、一緒、一緒と、はい、イェーイ！ イェーイ！
Neko, how about all you Nekos? Are you used to idols? Really? Ah, you're used to it, really? Yes, together, together, yeah, yay! Yay!
てことね、ねのさ、アイドリーソー、見てこれみんな！ ちょっと時間もったいないから、同時進行すすぜさん、これ見て！ ねっこのみんなとね、アイドルのね、ステージに一緒に立ちたくて、ここにね！
So, Nene's... Idol-y show, look at this everyone! We don't have much time, so let's do things simultaneously, look at this! I wanted to stand together on the idol stage with all the Nekos, right here!
つけてまたなんかこれさ、これとさ、一緒に、なんかサインでいい感じにさ、ちょっと待てよ、これを、そして、みんな、好き！
And wearing it, something like this, together with a nice signature, wait a moment, this, and then, everyone, I love you!
ななななな「な」じゃなくて
Nana nana, it's not "na"
ににににに「に」じゃなくて
Nini nini, it's not "ni"
ぬぬぬぬぬ「ぬ」じゃなくて
Nunu nunu, it's not "nu"
ののののの「の」じゃなくて
No nonono, it's not "no"
……「ね」！
...ne!
（ねね！）
(Nene!)
（ヨイショ ヨイショ
(Yoisho, yoisho
ヨイショ ヨイショ！）
yoisho, yoisho!)
（ねね！）
(Nene!)
（ヨイショ ヨイショ
(Yoisho, yoisho
ヨイショ ヨイショ！）
yoisho, yoisho!)
こんねね～！
Konnene~!
（こんねね～！）
(Konnene~!)
ホロライブ5期生 オレンジ担当
Hololive 5th Generation's orange representative,
桃鈴ねねです！
Momosuzu Nene!
（ねねち～！）
(Nenechi!)
異世界から来ました
I came from another world,
アイドル志望の
dreaming of being an idol,
新人Vtuber
a new VTuber
（何だって！？）
(What!?)
まぁ、
Well,
とにかく明るくいきましょう！
let's stay optimistic and go!
ちょっとくらい緊張したって、
Even if I feel a little nervous,
滑ったって
or slip and fall,
「うおー！」って感じでいこう
I'll shout "Oh!!" and keep going
（うおー！）
(Oh!!)
「どりゃあ！」ってやっていこう
with a "Doryaa!!"
（どりゃあ！）
(Doryaa!)
あきらめの悪さは長所だよね？
Being bad at giving up is one of my strong points, right?
ねねねねねねねねね
Ne nenene nenene nenene!
（ね！）
(Ne!)
ねねねねねねねねね
Ne nenene nenene nenene!
（ね！）
(Ne!)
「はぁ～ん」なこともあるけど
Sometimes things make me go "haa an"
悔しいこともあるけど大丈夫！
and sometimes they're painful, but I'll be alright!
今日もしかり、おめかしして
I'll dress up just fine today too,
いつかはきっと
and someday I'll be
「すーぱーねねちー！」
"Super Nenechi!"
ついてきて
Come with me,
ねねねねねね
ne nenene nenene
ねねねねねねねね
ne nene nene nenene
（ねね！）
(Nene!)
ねねねねねね
ne nene nene
（ね！）
(Ne!)
ねねねね
ne nene
（ね！）
(Ne!)
ねねねねねね
ne nene nene
（ねね！）
(Nene!)
って、全力で行こう！
and go at full power!
そんで全開で行こう！
Yep, I'll go at full throttle!
思い切りやれば何とかなるよ
If I give it all I've got it'll turn out okay!
ポンコツだっていい
Even if I'm clumsy it's okay!
（ヨイショ！）
(Yoisho!)
誤字ったっていい
Even if I make a typo it's okay!
（ヨイショ！）
(Yoisho!)
ただ駆け抜けていこうね
I'll just keep running through!
（ね！）
(Ne!)
ね！
Ne!
（ね！）
(Ne!)
ね！
Ne!
（ね！）
(Ne!)
ね！
Ne!
（ね！）
(Ne!)
ね！
Ne!
大爆走
It's a Nene nenene sprint!!
（ねね！）
(Nene!)
（ヨイショ ヨイショ
(Yoisho, yoisho
ヨイショ ヨイショ！）
yoisho, yoisho!)
（ねね！）
(Nene!)
（ヨイショ ヨイショ
(Yoisho, yoisho
ヨイショ ヨイショ！）
yoisho, yoisho!)
野菜ジュースと炭酸とお菓子、そろえて準備OK！
Veggie juice, fizzy drinks, and sweets, I have them all and I'm good to go!
でも朝は苦手
But I'm not a morning person,
（だね！）
(that's right!)
夜も苦手
and I'm not a night person,
（だね！）
(that's right!)
やっぱり睡眠って、大事だよね？
sleeping really is important, huh!
ねねねねねねねねね (ね！)
Ne ne nene ne nene ne nene (Ne!)
たくさんの人に、愛されたい！
I wanna be loved by lots of people!
ちゅちゅちゅ
Chu chu chu!
（ちゅちゅちゅ）
(Chu chu chu!)
ちゅちゅちゅ
Chu chu chu!
（ちゅちゅちゅ）
(Chu chu chu!)
大好きなみんなに、愛されたい！
I wanna be loved by my beloved fans!
ちゅちゅちゅ
Chu chu chu!
（ちゅちゅちゅ）
(Chu chu chu!)
ちゅちゅちゅ
Chu chu chu!
（ちゅちゅちゅ）
(Chu chu chu!)
そしたらなんなの
And then I'll become
「はいぱーねねちー！」
"Hyper Nenechi!!"
やっちゃって
Let's go for it,
ねねねねねね
ne nenene nenene
ねねねねねねねね (ねね！)
ne nene nene nenene (ne ne!)
ねねねねねね (ね！)
nene nene nene (ne!)
ねねねね (ね！)
ne nene (ne!)
ねねねねねね (ねね！)
nene nene nene (nene!)
って、全力で行こう！
and go at full power!
そんで全開で行こう！
Yep, I'll go at full throttle!
歌は誰にも負けないんだ
I don't wanna lose to anyone at singing!
大きな声で
With a loud voice—
（ヨイショ！）
(Yoisho!)
あ、その前に
Ah, but before that,
（ヨイショ！）
(Yoisho!)
ちょっとトイレ行ってくるね～
I need to go to the restroom real quick!
（restroom time！！）
(Restroom time!!)
（ねね！）
(Nene!)
（ヨイショ ヨイショ
(Yoisho, yoisho
ヨイショ ヨイショ！）
yoisho, yoisho!)
（ねね！）
(Nene!)
（ヨイショ ヨイショ
(Yoisho, yoisho
ヨイショ ヨイショ！）
yoisho, yoisho!)
ななななな「な」じゃなくて
Nana nana, it's not "na"
ににににに「に」じゃなくて
Nini nini, it's not "ni"
ぬぬぬぬぬ「ぬ」じゃなくて
Nunu nunu, it's not "nu"
ののののの「の」じゃなくて……
No nonono, it's not "no"...
ただいま～！
I'm back~!
最後に
And last,
ねねねねねね
ne nenene nenene
ねねねねねねねね (ねね！)
ne nene nene nenene (ne ne!)
ねねねねねね (ね！)
nene nene nene (ne!)
ねねねね (ね！)
ne nene (ne!)
ねねねねねね (ねね！)
nene nene nene (nene!)
って、全力で行こう！
and go at full power!
そんで全開で行こう！
Yep, I'll go at full throttle!
思い切りやれば何とかなるよ
If I give it all I've got it'll turn out okay!
ポンコツだっていい
Even if I'm clumsy it's okay!
（ヨイショ！）
(Yoisho!)
誤字ったっていい
Even if I make a typo it's okay!
（ヨイショ！）
(Yoisho!)
ただ駆け抜けていこうね
I'll just keep running through!
（ね！）
(Ne!)
ね！
Ne!
（ね！）
(Ne!)
ね！
Ne!
（ね！）
(Ne!)
ね！
Ne!
（ね！）
(Ne!)
ね！
Ne!
大爆走
It's a Nene nenene sprint!!
それじゃあ、またねね～
And with that, mata nene~!
（またねね～）
(Mata nene~)
ばいばーーい
Bye-bye!
じゃあ、あ、これだったらね、このみんなも見れるね、これ。
Well, with this, everyone can see it too.
じゃあ、ねこ、ねこの人も一緒にいこ？ねこの人、
So, shall Neko-san and the Neko people come along too? Neko-san,
はいねっこのみんな～！いぇーい！
yes, Neko's fans! Yay!
あ、そっか、ちょっと見えなくなっちゃう、こっちの、ちっちゃいみんなが見えなくなっちゃう。
Ah, right, the small ones over here won't be able to see anymore.
いぇーい！
Yay!
ここに、この指の先に載って。あ、いいぞいいぞいいぞいいぞ！いいバランスキープしてるね！いぇーい！
Hop on my fingertip. Ah, nice, nice, nice! You're keeping a great balance! Yay!
じゃあちょっとね、次のみんなにも繋げないといけないから、
So, since I need to pass the baton to everyone in the next slot,
そう、最後に、ちょっと最後に、スイッチに……！
finally, for the last switch...
これを使って、このまま進めたいと思います！
I'd like to use this and keep going just like this!
というわけで、ねねのパートももう終わりになっちゃうんですけど、
So, Nene's part is coming to an end,
みんなちょっと見足りないでしょ？
but you guys still want to see more, right?
でもね、アーカイブとかでもいっぱい見て、ねねのね、あのアイドルとして第一歩をみんなで一緒に進めたら
But you know, if you watch the archive a lot and we can take our first steps together as idols,
うれしいと思います！うれしいです！
I'd be so happy! I'd be so happy!
と言うわけで、次はね、ししろんの枠になりますので、みんなね、あ、間違えた！ししろんじゃない！次ねぽだから！ぽるからの、次、おまるんの枠なので、みんなで一緒におまるんの枠にいきましょう！というわけで、ねねの枠はここまで！
So next up is Botan's slot—ah, my bad! Not Botan! Next is Nepo—from Polka, next is Omarun's slot, so let's all go over to Omarun's slot together! And with that, Nene's slot is up!
またねね、みんな、ばいばいわーーい！最後にバチバチの写真、いぇい！
See you again, everyone, bye-bye-waaai! And finally, a super cool photo, yay!